Tiq Milan: Our first conversation was on Facebook,
(تيك ميلان): كان أول حديث لنا على فيسبوك،
and it was three days long.
والذي امتدّ لثلاثة أيام كاملة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We shared over 3,000 messages between us,
تبادلنا أكثر من 3000 رسالة فيما بيننا،
and it was during those 72 hours that I knew she was going to be my wife.
حينها عرفت أنها ستكون زوجتي.
We didn't wait any prerequisite amount of time for our courtship;
لم ننتظر أي وقت محدد مسبقاً نتودد فيه لبعضنا البعض؛
we told each other the vulnerable truths up front:
صارحنا بعضنا البعض بالحقائق الهشّة فينا:
I am a transgender man,
أنا رجل متحول جنسياً،
which means the F on my birth certificate should have stood for "False,"
مما يعني أن حرف الألف في شهادة ميلادي يجب أن يعني كلمة "مزيف،"
instead of "Female."
بدلاً عن "أنثى."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Walking around as a woman in the world
مواجهة العالم كامرأة
felt like walking with pebbles in my shoes.
كان أمراً مؤلماً للغاية.
It took the rhythm out of my swagger,
كان ذلك يقلّل من ثقتي بنفسي،
it threw me off balance,
وأخلّ بتوازني،
it pained me with every step I took forward.
وسبّب لي الألم مع كل خطوةٍ أخطوها للأمام.
But today I'm a man of my own intention;
لكن اليوم، أنا رجل نزولاً عند رغبتي الخاصة؛
a man of my own design.
رجلٌ كما أريد أن أكون.
Kim Katrin Milan: I am a cisgender queer woman.
(كيم كاترين ميلان): أنا امرأة شاذة طبيعية الجنس.
Cisgender means the gender I was assigned at birth
وذلك يعني الجنس الذي قدّر لي أن أكون وقت ميلادي
is still and has always been female.
كنت وما زلت امرأة.
This doesn't make me natural or normal,
هذا لا يجعلني طبيعيّة أو عاديّة،
this is just one way of describing the many different ways
بل هي طريقة من بين عدة طرق لوصف
that we exist in this world.
وجودنا في هذا العالم.
And queer is a cultural term,
كلمة شاذ هي مصطلح ثقافي،
but in this case,
ولكن في هذه الحالة،
it refers to the way that I'm not restricted by gender
تشير إلى كوني غير مقيّدة بجنس معين
when it comes to choosing partners.
عندما يتعلق الأمر باختيار شركاء.
I've identified in a few different ways --
تم تعريفي بعدة طرق مختلفة --
as a bisexual, as a lesbian --
كثنائية الجنس وكمثلية الجنس --
but for me,
ولكن بالنسبة لي،
queerness encompasses all of the layers of who I am and how I've loved.
الشذوذ يشمل كل هذه الطبقات لمن أكون وأحببت.
I'm layers, and not fractions.
أنا طبقات ولست أجزاء.
And for me,
وبالنسبة لي،
the fact that he was queer
حقيقة كونه شاذاً
meant that I could trust his courtship from the very beginning.
عنى أن بإمكاني أن أثق بتودّده لي منذ البداية.
As queer and trans people,
كشاذة وأخر متحول جنسياً،
we're so often excluded from institutions and traditions.
غالباً ما يتم استبعادنا من المؤسسات والتقاليد.
We create spaces outside of convention,
نحن نخلق مسافات خارج العرف
including the conventions of time.
بما فيها أعراف الوقت.
And in those 3,000 messages between us,
وفي تلك ال 3000 رسالة التي تبادلناها،
we collapsed time;
فقد هدمنا الوقت؛
we queered it;
حرفّناها؛
we laid it all on the table.
ووضعناها بالكامل على الطاولة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
With no pretense at all.
من دون أدنى تظاهر إطلاقاً.
And this meant that we were able to commit to each other
وعني ذلك أنّه كان بمقدورنا الإلتزام لبعضنا البعض
in a profoundly different way.
بطريقة مختلفة على نحو عميق.
So often what we're told is this idea of the "Golden Rule,"
لذلك غالباً ما يتم اخبارنا عن هذه "القاعدة الذهبية،"
that we should treat other people the way we want to be treated.
أنّه يتوجب علينا أن نعامل الأخرين بنفس الطريقة التي نحب أن نعامل بها.
But the problem with that
ولكن المشكلة في ذلك
is that it assumes that we are the standard for other people,
أنه يفترض أنّنا المقياس للأخرين،
and we're not.
وذلك ليس بصحيح.
We need to treat other people the way they want to be treated,
نحن بحاجة أن نعامل الأخرين بالطريقة التي يحبّون أن يعاملوا بها،
which means we had to ask.
ما يعني أنه يتوجب علينا أن نسأل.
I couldn't assume that the kind of love that Tiq needed
لم أستطع أن أفترض أن نوع الحب الذي احتاج إليه (تيك)
was the same kind of love that I needed.
كان هو نفس نوع الحب الذي احتجته أنا.
So I asked him everything -- about his fears, his insecurities --
لذلك سألته عن كل شيء -- عن مخاوفه، واحساسه بعدم الأمان --
and we started from there.
ومن هناك كانت بدايتنا.
TM: I didn't know what kind of love I needed.
(تيك): لم أكن أعي نوع الحب الذي كنت بحاجة له.
I had just come out of a year-long fog
كنت خارجاً للتو من سنة طويلة يلفها الضباب
of being rejected and utterly depleted.
حيث كنت أتعرض للرفض واستنفدت بالكامل.
I had someone look me in my eyes
حدث أن نظر لي أحدهم
and tell me that I was unworthy of their love because I was trans.
وقال لي أنّني غير جدير بحبهم لأنّني متحول جنسياً.
And there's a culture of lovelessness
وكذلك وجود ثقافة عدم المحبة
that we've created around transgender people.
التي خلقناها حول الأشخاص متحولي الجنس.
It's reasoned, justified and often signed into law.
هذا الأمر مسبّب له ومبرر وغالباً ما يتم تمريره كقانون.
And I was a heartbeat away from internalizing that message,
وقد كنت على مقربة من استيعاب تلك الرسالة،
that I wasn't worthy.
أنّني لا أستحق.
But Kim said that I was her ideal --
لكن (كيم) قالت أنّني رجلها المثالي --
the heartbroken mess that I was.
بكل الفوضى المفجعة التي كنت عليها
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
KKM: He totally was my ideal.
(كيم): كان رجلي المثالي بالفعل.
In more ways than one.
بأكثر من طريقة.
Both poets, writers, creatives
كلا الشاعرين والكاتبين والمبدعين
with a long history of community work behind us,
مع تاريخ طويل من العمل المجتمعي خلفنا،
and big, huge dreams of a family in front of us,
وأحلام ضخمة لتأسيس عائلة أمامنا،
we shared a lot of things in common,
تشاركنا الكثير من الأشياء،
but we were also incredibly different.
كنّا مختلفين أيضاً على نحو لا يصدق.
I've been a lifelong traveler and a bit of an orphan,
كنت شخصاً محباً للسفر طول حياتي ويتيمة نوعاً ما،
whereas he comes from a huge family,
بينما أتى هو من عائلة كبيرة،
and definitely stays grounded.
وبالتأكيد ظلّ مرتبطاً بها.
I often kind of sum up the differences in our strengths
غالباً ما ألخّص الإختلافات في نقاط قوتنا
by saying, "Keep me safe,
بالقول، "حافظ علي بأمان،
and I'll keep you wild."
وسأبقيك جامحاً."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
TM: We have marginalized identities but we don't live marginalized lives.
(تيك): لدينا هويّات مهمّشة ولكنّنا لا نحيا حياةً مهمّشة.
Being queer and trans is about creating new ways of existing.
كونّنا شاذة ومتحول جنسياً يتمحور حول خلقنا لطرق تعايش جديدة.
It's about loving people as they are,
الأمر كله متعلق بحب الأخرين كما هم،
not as they're supposed to be.
وليس كما يفترض بهم أن يكونوا.
Kim is unapologetically feminine
(كيم) أنثوية على نحو غير قابل للإعتذار
in a world that is often cruel and violent
في عالمٍ غالباً ما يكون قاسياً وعنيفاً
to women who are too proud and too freeing.
تجاه النساء اللواتي يشعرن بالفخر والتحرر الشديد.
And I didn't enter into this union
ولم أدخل هذا الإتحاد
under the auspices that she was going to be my helper or my rib,
تحت رعاية أنها سوف تكون مساعدتي أو عوني،
but a fully complex --
لكنه معقّد تماماً --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
KKM: Right? That's not right.
(كيم): أليس كذلك؟ ليس ذلك بصحيح.
TM: But a fully complex human being
(تيك): لكن إنسانةً معقدةً تماماً
whose femininity wasn't for me to rein in, control or critique.
لم يتح لي السيطرة على أنوثتها أو التحكم فيها أو انتقادها.
It's her brilliance,
بل كان ذكاؤها،
the way she leads with compassion,
الشفقة البادية في تعاملها،
and how she never loses sight of her empathy.
كما أنها لا تفقد تعاطفها أبداً.
She has been my hero since day one.
ظلّت بطلتي منذ اليوم الأول.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
KKM: Our relationship has always been about setting each other free.
(كيم): لطالما تمحورت علاقتنا حول إتاحة الحرية لكلينا.
One of the first questions I asked him
كان من ضمن أول الأسئلة التي أسأله لها
was what dreams he had left to accomplish,
عن ما تبقى له من أحلام لتحقيقها،
and how would I help him get there.
وكيف يمكنني أن أساعده لتحقيقها.
His dreams to live as a poet,
أحلامه في أن يعيش كشاعر،
to adopt and raise a family together,
أن نتبنى وننشئ عائلة معاً،
to live a life that he was proud of,
أن نحيا حياة يكون هو فخوراً بها،
and one that would live up to his mother's incredible legacy.
حياةً يمكن أن ترقى لإرث أمه الذي لا يصدق.
And I really appreciated that we were able to start from that place,
وقد قدّرت حقاً أنه كان باستطاعتنا البدء من ذلك المكان،
and not from a place that was around figuring out
وليس من منطلق معرفة
how to make each other work together.
كيف لنا أن نتكيف مع بعضنا البعض.
And I think this really allowed us to grow into the people that we were
وأعتقد أن هذا أتاح لنا أن نكبر لما أصبحنا عليه
in a way that was incredibly different.
بطريقة كانت مخنلفة على نحو لا يصدق.
I love him whole;
أحبه بشدّة؛
pre-transition, now and in the future.
قبل التحوّل والأن وفي المستقبل.
And it's this love that had us committed to each other
وهذا الحب هو سبب التزامنا لبعضنا البعض
before we'd even seen each other's faces.
حتى قبل أن نرى بعضنا البعض.
TM: My mother's biggest concern when I transitioned
(تيك): كانت أكبر مخاوف أمي حينما تحوّلت
was who was going to love me as I am.
هي من سيحبني بالحال الذي سأصير عليه.
Had being transgender somehow precluded me from love and monogamy
كوني كنت متحولاً جنسياً، حال دون وقوعي في الحب أو الإرتباط
because I was supposedly born in the wrong body?
هل لأنّي فرضاً ولدت في الجسد الخطأ؟
But it's this type of structuring that has to be reframed
ولكنّه هذا النوع من البناء الذي يجب أن تعاد صياغته
in order to let love in.
كي نسمح للحب بالدخول.
My body never betrayed me,
لم يخنّي جسدي على الإطلاق،
and my body was never wrong.
ولم يكن جسدي خطأً على الإطلاق.
It's this restrictive, binary thinking on gender
كله بسبب هذا التفكير الثنائي المقيّد عن الجنس
that said that I didn't exist.
والذي أفتى بعدم وجودي.
But when we met,
ولكن عندما تقابلنا،
she loved me for exactly how I showed up.
أحبّتني بالشكل الذي بدوت عليه تماماً.
She would trace her fingers along the numb keloid scars
كانت تقتفي بأصابعها أثار الندبات الجدريّة المخدرة
left by my top surgery.
التي خلفتها الجراحة في الجزء العلوي.
Scars that run from the middle of my chest all the way out to my outer torso.
الندبات التي امتدت من منتصف صدري وحتى جذعي الخارجي.
She said that these were reminders of my strength
قالت أنها تمثّل تذكيراً لمدى قوتي
and everything that I went through
وكلّ ما مررت به
and nothing for me to be ashamed of.
وليس هناك من شيء يدفعني للخجل.
So sprinting towards her hand in marriage
لذلك كانت مطالبتها بالزواج
was the queerest thing that I could do.
أغرب شيء تمكنت من فعله.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It flew in the face of more conventional trajectories
واجه الأمر مسارات أكثر تقليدية
of love and relationships,
من الحب والعلاقات العاطفية،
because God was never supposed to bless a union for folks like us,
لأن الله ما كان ليبارك اتحاد أشخاص مثلنا،
and the law was never supposed to recognize it.
وما كان القضاء ليعترف به.
KKM: So on May 5, 2014,
(كيم): في الخامس من مايو عام 2014،
just about three months after meeting online,
بعد حوالي ثلاثة أشهر فقط من لقائنا عبر الإنترنت،
we were married on the steps of City Hall in Manhattan,
تزوّجنا عند عتبات (قاعة المدينة) في مدينة (مانهاتن)،
and it was beautiful in every conceivable way.
وقد كان جميلاً على نحو فاق كل التصورات.
It's safe to say that we reimagined some traditions,
من الأسلم أن نقول أنّنا أعدنا تخطيط بعض التقاليد،
but we also kept some old ones that we worked in,
كما أنّنا أيضاً أبقينا على بعض القديم منها،
and we created something that worked for us.
وخلقنا شيئاً يناسبنا نحن.
My bouquet and corsage was actually filled with wildflowers from Brooklyn --
كانت باقة أزهاري وصدر فستاني مليئاً بأزهار برية من (بروكلين) --
also added in a little bit of lavender and sage to keep us grounded
مع إضافة قليل من الخزامى والمريمية لإبقائنا ثابتين
because we were so nervous.
لأنّنا كنّا متوتري الأعصاب للغاية.
And it was put together by a sweet sister healer friend of ours.
وقد قامت صديقة معالجة هي أخت رائعة لنا بترتيبها.
I never wanted a diamond ring,
لم أطلب خاتماً ماسياً،
because conflict and convention are not my thing,
لأنّ الصراع والعرف لم يمثّلا شيئاً لي،
so my ring is the deepest purple,
لذلك كان البنفسجي الغامق هو خاتمي،
like the color of my crown chakra,
مثل لون الشاكرا التاجية خاصتي،
and set in place with my birthstones.
ووضع في مكان مع جوهرة مولدي.
The gift of queerness is options.
الغرابة تفضي إلى الخيارات.
I never had to choose his last name,
لم يتوجب علي اختيار اسمه الأخير،
it was never an exception,
لم يكن الأمر استثناءً،
but I did because I am my father's bastard child,
بل فعلت ذلك لأنّني طفلة والدي غير الشرعية،
someone who has always been an apology, a secret, an imposition.
شخص لطالما كان اعتذارً وسراً وفرضاً.
And it was incredibly freeing
وقد كانت حريةً لا تصدق
to choose the name of a man who chose me first.
أن أختار اسم الرجل الذي اختارني أولاً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
TM: So we told some family and some close friends,
(تيم): لذلك أخبرنا بعض أفراد العائلة وبعض الأصدقاء المقربين،
many of whom were still in disbelief as we took our vows.
العديد ممن كانوا غير مصدّقين بينما كنّا نحلف القسم.
Fittingly, we posted all of our wedding photos on Facebook,
على نحو ملائم، نشرنا صور زفافنا بالكامل على (فيسبوك)،
where we met --
حيث التقينا --
and Instagram, of course.
وكذلك (إنستغرام) بالتأكيد.
And we quickly realized
ولقد لاحظنا بسرعة
that our coming together was more than just a union of two people,
أن ارتباطنا ببعضنا البعض كان أكثر من مجرد اتحاد شخصين،
but was a model of possibility for the millions of LGBTQ folks
بل كان نموذجاً ممكن الحدوث للملايين من مجتمع LGBTQ لمثليي الجنس
who have been sold this lie
الذين صدّقوا هذه الكذبة
that family and matrimony is antithetical to who they are --
أن العائلة والزواج شيء متناقض مع وضعهم --
for those of us who rarely get to see ourselves
لنا نحن الذين نادراً ما نرى أنفسنا
reflected in love and happiness.
في صورة الحب والسعادة.
KKM: And the thing is,
(كيم): والأمر هو،
absolutely we are marginalized because of our identities,
أنّنا مهمّشون بالمعنى الحرفي للكلمة بسبب هوياتنا،
but it also emboldens us to be the people that we are.
ولكن ذلك يقوّينا لنكون ما نحن عليه.
Queerness is our major key;
الغرابة هي مفتاحنا الأساسي؛
blackness is our magic.
السواد هو سحرنا.
It's because of these things
يعود الفضل لهذه الأشياء
that we are able to be hopeful, open, receptive and shape-shifting.
في كوننا قادرين على أن نتحلى بالأمل وأن نكون منفتحين ومتقبلين ومتحولي الشكل.
These are the things that give us,
هذه هي الأشياء التي تمدّنا،
and are such an incredible source of, our strength.
وهي مصدر لا يصدق لقوتنا.
Our queerness is a source of that strength.
غرابتنا هي مصدر تلك القوة.
I think of the words of Ottawa-based poet Brandon Wint:
أفكّر في كلمات شاعر (أوتاوا) (براندون وينت) الذي قال:
"Not queer like gay; queer like escaping definition.
"ليس شاذاً كمثلي جنس؛ بل شاذاً في الهروب من التعريف.
Queer like some sort of fluidity and limitlessness all at once.
شاذاً كشيء من السيولة واللامحدودية على نحو غير متوقع.
Queer like a freedom too strange to be conquered.
شاذاً كحرية غريبة لحدّ لا يقهر.
Queer like the fearlessness to imagine what love can look like,
شاذاً كعدم الخوف من تخيّل ما قد يبدو عليه الحب،
and to pursue it."
والسعي خلفه."
TM: We are part of a community of folks --
(تيم): نحن جزء من مجتمع أناس --
Yeah, that's good right?
نعم، ذلك رائع أليس كذلك؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We are part of a community of folks who are living their authentic selves
نحن جزء من مجتمع أناس يعيشون ذواتهم الأصيلة
all along the gender spectrum,
ضمن طيف الجنسين،
despite the ubiquitous threat of violence,
على الرغم من التهديد الماثل بالعنف،
despite the undercurrent of anxiety that always is present
على الرغم من تيار القلق المستتر الحاضر دوماً
for people who live on their own terms.
بالنسبة للأشخاص الذين يعيشون حسب رؤاهم الخاصة.
Globally, a transgender person is murdered every 21 hours.
عالمياً، كل 21 ساعة يقتل شخص متحول جنسياً.
And the United States has had more trans murders on record this year
ولقد ضربت أمريكا رقماً قياساً لعدد المتحولين جنسياً الذين قتلوا هذا العام
than any year to date.
أكثر من أي عامٍ مضى.
However, our stories are much more than this rigid dichotomy
على أي حال، فإن قصصنا أكثر بكثير من هذا الإنقسام الجامد
of strength and resilience.
للقوة والمرونة.
We are expanding the human complexity on these margins,
نحن نعمل على توسيع التعقيد البشري في هذه الهوامش،
and we are creating freedom on these margins.
ونخلق الحرية في هذه الهوامش.
KKM: And we don't have any blueprints.
(كيم): كما أنه ليس لدينا أي خطط.
We're creating a world that we have literally never seen before;
نحن نخلق عالماً لم نره حرفياً من قبل؛
organizing families based on love and not by blood,
ننظم أسراً استنادً على الحب وليس رابطة الدم،
guiding by a compassion that so few of us have been shown ourselves.
كما نقود بالتراحم الذي تمتع به عدد قليل منا.
So many of us have not received love from our families --
لم يحظى العديد منّا بالحب من أسرهم --
have been betrayed by the people that we trust most.
تعرّضنا للخيانة من أشخاص وثقنا بهم بشدة.
So what we do here is we create entirely new languages of love.
لذلك ما نفعله هنا هو أنّنا نخلق بالكامل لغات حب جديدة.
Ones that are about creating the space for us to be our authentic selves
تلك المتعلقة بخلق مسافات لنا لنكون ذواتنا الأصيلة
and not imposing this standard
وأن لا نفرض هذا المعيار
of what masculinity or femininity is supposed to be.
لما يجب أن تكون عليه الذكورة أو الأنوثة.
TM: We are interested in love and inclusion
(تيم): نحن مهتمّون بالحب والتضمين
as a tool of revolutionary change, right?
كأداة للتغيير الثوري، أليس كذلك؟
And the idea is simply,
والفكرة ببساطة هي،
if we drop all our preconceived notions
إذا ما أسقطنا كل مفاهيمنا المسبقة
about how somebody is supposed to be --
عن ما يفترض أن يكون عليه شخص ما --
in their body, in their gender, in their skin --
بالنسبة لجسده وجنسه ولونه --
if we take the intentional steps to unlearn these deep-seated biases
إذا ما خطونا خطوات جادة لطرح هذه التحيّزات عميقة الجذور جانباً
and create space for people to be self-determined,
وخلقنا مساحة للناس ليحدّدوا ذواتهم،
and embrace who they are,
وتقبّلنا ما هم عليه،
then we will definitely create a better world than the one we were born into.
حينها بالتأكيد سنخلق عالماً أفضل من الذي وجدنا أنفسنا فيه.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
KKM: We want to mark this time in history
(كيم): نريد أن نضع بصمتنا في التاريخ
by leaving evidence of the fact that we were here.
بأن نترك الدليل على أنّنا كنّا هنا.
We open up little windows into our relationship
نحن نفتح نوافذ صغيرة تحكي عن علاقتنا
for our community to bear witness,
لصالح مجتمعنا حتى يشهد عليها،
and we do this because we want to make maps to the future
ونحن نفعل هذا لأنّنا نريد أن نرسم خرائط للمستقبل
and not monuments to ourselves.
وليس صروحاً لأنفسنا.
Our experience does not invalidate other peoples' experience,
فتجربتنا لا تبطل تجارب الأخرين،
but it should and necessarily does complicate this idea
ولكنها يجب وبالضرورة أن تعقّد هذه الفكرة
of what love and marriage are supposed to be.
بخصوص ما يفترض أن يكون عليه الحب والزواج.
TM: OK, now for all the talking,
(تيم): حسناً، من أجل الحديث،
and inspiring,
والإلهام،
and possibility-modeling we've done,
ونموذج الإمكانية الذي أرسيناه،
we've been nowhere near perfect.
لم نكن قريبين أبداً من الكمال.
And we've had to hold a mirror up to ourselves.
وكان يتوجب علينا أن نمسك بمرآة لأنفسنا.
And I saw that I wasn't always the best listener,
ولقد فطنت إلى أنّني لست بمستمع جيد دائماً،
and that my ego got in the way of our progress as a couple.
وأن الأنا عندي تقف في طريق تقدمنا كزوجين.
And I've had to really assess these deep-seated, sexist ideas
كما توجّب علي تقييم هذه الأفكار الراسخة والجنسية
that I've had about the value of a woman's experience in the world.
والتي كانت في ذهني حول قيمة تجربة المرأة في العالم.
I've had to reevaluate what it means to be in allyship with my wife.
توجب علي إعادة تقييم ما يعنيه أن أكون طرفاً في علاقة مع زوجتي.
KKM: And I had to remind myself of a lot of things, too.
(كيم): كما توجب علي أن أذّكر نفسي بالعديد من الأشياء أيضاً.
What it means to be hard on the issues,
عن ما يعنيه أن تكون متزمتاً تجاه القضايا،
but soft on the person.
ولكن ليناً مع الشخص المعني.
While we were writing this, we got into a massive fight.
بينما كنّا نكتب هذا، انخرطنا في عراك كبير.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
For so many different reasons,
لأسباب مختلفة عدّة،
but based on the content about our values and our lived experiences --
ولكن استندنا على المحتوى المتعلق بقيمنا وتجاربنا المعاشة --
and we were really hurt, you know?
ولقد تعرضنا للأذية حقاً، أتعلمون؟
Because what we do and how we love puts ourselves entirely on the line.
لأن ما نفعله وكيف نحب وضعنا تماماً في خط المواجهة.
But even though the fight lasted over the course of two days --
ولكن رغم ذلك، امتد العراك لفترة يومين --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We were able to come back together to each other,
كان بمقدورنا العودة لبعضنا البعض،
and recommit to ourselves, to each other and to our marriage.
والالتزام مجدداً لبعضنا البعض وبزواجنا.
And that really yielded some of the most passionate parts
وقد أثمر ذلك حقاً في بعض الأجزاء الأكثر عاطفية
of what we share with you here today.
لما تشاركناه معكم هنا، اليوم.
TM: I have had to interrogate masculinity,
(تيم): توجّب علىّ وضع الذكورة موضع التساؤل،
which I think doesn't happen enough.
والذي لم يصل للحد الكافي بعد.
I've had to interrogate masculinity;
توجّب عليّ وضع الذكورة موضع التساؤل؛
the toxic privileges that come with being a man don't define me,
الإمتيازات المسمّمة التي تصْحُبُ كوني رجلاً، لا تمثلني،
but I have to be accountable for how it shows up in my life every day.
ولكنّني يجب أن أكون مسؤولاً عن ما يبدر منّي في الحياة اليومية.
I have allowed my wife to do all of the emotional labor
سمحت لزوجتي بأن تتكفّل بكل الحمْل العاطفي
of prying open the lines of communication when I'd rather clam up and run away.
المتعلق بالتطفل وفتح خطوط الإتصال بينما أصمت أنا وأهرب بعيداً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I've stripped away emotional support instead of facing my own vulnerabilities,
لقد تجرّدت من الدعم العاطفي بدلاً من مواجهة نقاط ضعفي،
particularly around the heartbreaking miscarriage we suffered last year,
ولا سيّما المتعلق بالإجهاض المفجع الذي عانينا منه العام الماضي،
and I'm sorry for that.
وأنا أشعر بالأسف لذلك.
Sometimes as men, we get to take the easy way out.
أحياناً كرجال، نتّخذ الطريق السهل.
And so my journey as a trans person is about reimagining masculinity.
ولذلك كشخص متحول جنسياً، فإن رحلتي عبارة عن إعادة تخيّل للذكورة.
About creating a manhood that isn't measured
عن خلق رجولة لا تقاس
by the power it wields, by the entitlements afforded to it,
بالقوة التي تمتلكها، والاستحقاقات الممنوحة لها،
or any simulacrum of control that it can muster,
أو أي صورة تحكّم زائفة يمكن لها حشدها،
but works in tandem with femininity,
ولكن تعمل جنباً إلى جنب مع الأنوثة،
and is guided by my spirit.
وتقودها روحي أنا.
KKM: Y'all ...
(كيم): جميعكم ...
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And this has created the space for my femininity to flourish
ولقد خلق هذا المساحة لأنوثتي لتزهر.
in a way I had never experienced before.
بطريقة لم أعهدها من قبل.
He never is threatened by my sexuality,
هو ليس مهدّداً أبداً بحياتي الجنسية،
he never polices what I wear or how I act.
كما أنه لا يراقب أبداً ما أرتدي أو كيف أتصرف.
I cook but he does way more of the cleaning than I do.
أطهو الطعام ولكنه يقوم بأعمال النظافة أكثر مني.
And when we're rushing to get out of the house
وعندما نهمّ بالخروج من المنزل مسرعين
and we have so much to handle,
ولدينا الكثير من الإرتباطات،
he handles everything,
فهو يتولى كل شيء،
so I have time to do my hair and makeup.
لذلك يتوفر لي الوقت، لأصفّف شعري وأضع زينتي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
He understands that this is my armor,
هو يفهم أن هذا درعي،
and he never treats femininity as though it is frivolous or superficial,
ولا يعامل الأنوثة أبداً على أنها شيء تافه أو سطحي،
and this, and him --
وهذا، وهو --
he grows my experience of gender every single day.
إنه يجعل تجربتي مع الجنس تكبر يوماً بعد يوم.
TM: I love to watch her get dressed in the morning.
(تيم): أحب متابعتها وهي ترتدي ثيابها صباحاً.
Watching her in the closet,
النظر إليها وهي في الخزانة،
looking for something comfortable and colorful, and tight,
باحثةً عن شيء مريح وملوّن وضيّق
and safe --
وآمن --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it's challenging to watch her negotiate her decisions
ولكن مشاهدتها وهي تتفاوض حول قراراتها تنطوي على تحدي
looking for something that's going to get the least amount of attention,
باحثةً عن شيء يوفر لها الحد الأدنى من الإنتباه،
but at the same time be an expression of the vibrant and sexy woman she is.
ولكن في الوقت نفسه يكون تعبيراً عن ما تمثله من حيوية وإثارة.
And all I want to do is celebrate her for her beauty,
وكل ما أودّ فعله هو أن أحتفي بجمالها،
and the things that make her beautiful and special and free,
وكل الأِشياء التي تجعلها جميلة ومميزة وحرّة،
from her long acrylic nails,
كأظافرها الإكريليكية الطويلة،
to her uncompromising black feminism.
وحتى نسويتها السوداء العنيدة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
KKM: I love you. TM: I love you.
-(كيم): أحبك. -(تيك): أحبك.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
KKM: There are so many queer and trans people
(كيم): يوجد الكثير من الشواذ والمتحولين جنسياً
who have come before us,
الذين سبقونا،
whose stories we will never get to hear.
والذين سوف لن نتمكن من سماع قصصهم.
We constantly experience this retelling of history
نواجه باستمرار إعادة التاريخ هذه
where we are conspicuously left out.
حيث يتم إقصاؤنا على نحو واضح.
And it's really hard to not see ourselves there.
ومن الصعب حقاً أن لا نرى أنفسنا هناك.
And so living out loud for us is about that representation.
لذلك بالنسبة لنا فإن الجهر بصوتنا يتعلق بذلك التمثيل.
It's about having possibility models,
الأمر يتعلق بوجود نماذج الإمكانية،
and having hope that love is part of our inheritance in this world, too.
ووجود الأمل أن الحب هو جزء من إرثنا في هذا العالم أيضاً.
TM: The possibility that we are practicing
(تيم): الإمكانية التي نمارسها
is about reinventing time, love and institutions.
تدور حول إعادة إختراع الوقت والحب والمؤسسات.
We are creating a future of multiplicity.
نحن نعمل على خلق مستقبل التعددية.
We are expanding the spectrum of gender and sexuality,
نحن نعمل على توسيع طيف الجنس والحياة الجنسية،
imagining ourselves into existence,
متتخيّلين أنفسنا في حيز الوجود،
imagining a world where gender is self-determined and not imposed,
متخيّلين عالماً حيث يكون فيه الجنس قرارً ذاتياً وليس مفروضاً،
and where who we are is a kaleidoscope of possibility
وحيث نكون مشكالاً متغير الألوان للإمكانية
without the narrow-minded limitations masquerading as science or justice.
دون القيود ضيقة الأفق المتخفّية في شكل العلوم والعدالة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
KKM: And I can't lie:
(كيم): ومن دون كذب:
it is really, really hard.
إنه لشيء صعب جداً جداً.
It is hard to stand in the face of bigotry
من الصعب أن أقف في وجه التعصب
with an open heart and a smile on my face.
بقلب منفتح وابتسامةٍ تعلو وجهي.
It is really hard to face the injustice that exists in the world,
من الصعب جداً أن تواجه الظلم المستشري في العالم،
while still believing in the ability of people to really change.
بينما تظلّ مؤمناً بقدرة الناس على إحداث تغيير حقيقي.
That takes an enormous amount of faith and dedication.
الشيء الذي يتطلب قدراً هائلاً من الإيمان والتفاني.
And beyond that,
وأكثر من ذلك،
marriage is hard work.
الزواج عمل صعب.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Piles of dirty socks on the floor,
أكوام من الجوارب القذرة ملقاة على الأرض،
more boring sports shows than I ever thought possible --
برامج رياضية مملة أكثر بكثير من ما توقعت وجوده --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And fights that bring me to tears
والمعارك التي تدفعني إلى ذرف الدموع
when it feels like we're not speaking the same language.
عندما يبدو الأمر أنّنا غير متفاهمين.
But there is not a day that goes by
ولكن لم يمر يومٌ
where I am not so grateful to be married to this man;
دون أن أشعر فيه بالإمتنان لأنّني تزوجت من هذا الرجل؛
where I'm not so grateful for the possibility of changing minds,
دون أن أشعر بالإمتنان لإمكانية تغيير العقول،
and rewarding conversations,
ومكافأة الحوارات،
and creating a world where love belongs to us all.
وخلق عالم ينتمي فيه الحب لنا جميعاً.
I think about our acronym:
أفكر في تسميتنا المختصرة:
LGBTQ2SIA.
LGBTQ2SIA
A seemingly endless evolution of self and a community,
على ما يبدو، تطوّر لا نهائي للذات والمجتمع،
but also this really deep desire not to leave anyone behind.
ولكن أيضاً هذه الرغبة الجارفة أن لا نترك أحداً خلفنا.
We've learned how to love each other,
لقد تعّلمنا كيف نحب بعضنا البعض،
and we've committed to loving each other throughout changes to gender
ولقد التزمنا بأن نحب بعضنا البعض على طول التغيرات في الجنس
and changes in spirit.
والتغيرات في الروح.
And we learned this love in our chat rooms,
كما تعلّمنا أن هذا الحب هو غرف الدردشة الخاصة بنا،
in our clubs, in our bars and in our community centers.
في نوادينا وحاناتنا ومراكزنا الإجتماعية.
We've learned how to love each other for the long haul.
لقد تعلّمنا كيف نحب بعضنا البعض لفترة طويلة.
TM &amp; KKM: Thank you.
(تيم وتيك): شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)